A Guide to the Drawings by Oscar Edward Cesare 1912-1943
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
- Untitled August 11, 1935 (Oversize C17)
  Uncle Sam and [Great Britain ?] looking at a gallery of paintings showing contrasts between the two countries
- "Most Members Actually Dread the Return Home" September 8, 1935 (Oversize C17)
  Referring to Congress
- The God of War surveying the earth September 29, 1935 (Oversize C17)
- "Fascism's Progress" November 3, 1935 (Oversize C17)
  Picture of a tank overrunning humanity and attacking the wall of freedom
- Untitled November 15, 1936 (Oversize C17)
  Symbolic figures representing Great Britain and France stand up to a figure representing Nazism and Communism
- Untitled August 8, 1937 (Oversize C17)
  The iron fists of fascism manipulating art, science, education, the courts, business, the stage, and the press like puppets
- Untitled October 3, 1937 (Oversize C17)
  Franklin D. Roosevelt pictured as the telephone operator for the nation
- "The Gamble of the Dictators" December 26, 1937 (Oversize C17)
  Picture of several dictators playing for the earth in a game of roulette
- Untitled January 9, 1938 (Oversize C17)
  A figure of Liberty standing in the gap of trade barriers
- "A Man is the Issue Once More - Franklin D. Roosevelt" October 4, 1938 (Oversize C17)
- "Destroy the Bill of Rights and Freedom Will Pass from America as Surely as Day Passes Into Night" November 20, 1938 (Oversize C17)
- Untitled December 11, 1938 (Oversize C17)
  The Monroe Doctrine protecting both South and North America
- "The War Machine in Gear - 1939" April 2, 1939 (Oversize C17)
- "Hitler's Growing Reich - 1933-1939" April 9, 1939 (Oversize C17)
- "[Depuy?] nach osten 1914-1939" (1939 ?) (Oversize C17)
- "Whatever the degree of sound and color...the truth is that a national political convention is a highly directed affair" June 16, 1940 (Oversize C17)
- Uncle Sam Looks at Europe "This appalling tragedy teaches us that we must face up to the responsibilities of defense, regardless of personal sacrifice" President Roosevelt June 30, 1940 (Oversize C17)
- Untitled July 21, 1940 (Oversize C17)
  The Monroe Doctrine shielding the Americas from Nazism
- "Uncle Sam Draws the Line" September 15, 1940 (Oversize C17)
  For defense of the Western Hemisphere
- "America 1940-1941" December 16, 1940 (Oversize C17)
  Uncles Sam producing war materials
- "After twenty-two years" (1940) (Oversize C17)
  France once again confronts German aggression
- Illustration for Edna St. Vincent Millay's Verses Saint George and the DragonDecember 28, 1941 (Oversize C17)
- "The American Student of History Reviews his Great History" May 3, 1942 (Oversize C17)
- "The Soldiers" June 21, 1942 (Oversize C17)
  Speaking of both the enlisted soldier and the industrial worker
- "A Friend in Need and the Open Road" April 25, 1943 (Oversize C17)
- "The Task of the Big Four is to Avert a Third World War" May 9, 1943 (Oversize C17)
- "The Jig-Saw Puzzle of Peace" May 30, 1943 (Oversize C17)
- The American Eagle Delivering its Peace Plan June 27, 1943 (Oversize C17)
- Untitled July 18, 1943 (Oversize C17)
  A Hand Pointing the Way for An American Soldier with the Soldiers of 1918 in the Background
- "Allied Dissension" August 8, 1943 (Oversize C17)
- "Business is Business" August 22, 1943 (Oversize C17)
- "Our Destiny is Bound Up With the Re-discovery of This Heritage" September 20, 1943 (Oversize C17)
- Uncle Sam and a British Figure Looking Over the Globe October 2, 1943 (Oversize C17)
- War Ration Books make sure the soldier is able to eat October 24, 1943 (Oversize C17)
- "The Peace of the World Must Rest Upon the Spirit if Not Letter of Woodrow Wilson's Memorable Pledge to Mankind" November 14, 1943 (Oversize C17)
- "The Popular Will For Peace Must Prevail Over the Obstructionists" December 12, 1943 (Oversize C17)
- "The Neighbors United States and Soviet Russia" January 2, 1944 (Oversize C17)
- "The Land of the Rising Sun" n.d. (Oversize C17)
  Pictured as an octopus
- "The Last Laugh" n.d. (Oversize C17)
  The American Armed Forces about to strike the Axis Powers with the Offensive while the Axis Powers are examining the fighting forces of 1940 with a magnifying glass
- Italo Balbo, Under Secretary of National Economy, One of the Four Who Led the Black-Shirts on Rome n.d. (Oversize C17)
- Filippo Cremonesi, Governor of Rome, Oldest of the Important Fascist Officials) 1926 (Oversize C17)
- [David Lloyd George ?] 1922 (Oversize C17)
- Dino Grandi, Under Secretary of Foreign Affairs (3 drawings) n.d. (Oversize C17)
- Benito Mussolini (2 drawings) May 31, 1926 (Oversize C17)
- Edgar Allan Poe 1926 (Oversize C17)
- Margherita Sarfatti, Biographer of Mussolini and Fascist Historian, First Active Woman Fascist, Well-Known Critic on Literature and Art (2 drawings) 1926 (Oversize C17)
- Unidentified [fascists ?] (2 drawings) 1927 (Oversize C17)
- Attilio Teruzzi, Under Secretary of Interior Affairs (2 drawings) n.d. (Oversize C17)
- Theodore Roosevelt pictured as a Trojan Horse by [Olha ?] Cushing n.d. (Oversize 60)
- "Simple Solution of the Panama Labor Problem. Let Our Superfluous Citizens Do the Work" in Puck by [Ehrhart ?] n.d. (Oversize 60)